我们真该带带猎枪来处理这种事情
We should have shot guns for this kind of deal
上面有多少人？
How many up there?
三、四个吧
Three or four
包括我们的人?
That's counting our guy?
不确定
I'm not sure
所以有可能五个人
So that means it could be up to five guys up there?
很有可能
It's possible
真他妈该拿猎枪来的！
We should have fucking shotguns
她叫什么?
What's her name?
米娅        米娅?
Mia  Mia?
马瑟勒斯怎么认识她的
How did Marsellus and her meet?
谁知道呢 就这么认识的
I don't know  However people meet people
她当过演员
She used to be an actress
是吗?她演过什么?
Oh, really? She do anything I'd have seen?
我想她最重要的演出就是一个样片儿吧
I think her biggest deal was she starred in a pilot
“样片”是什么玩意?
Pilot? What's a pilot?
呃…看过电视剧吧?
Well, you know the shows on TV?
我从不看电视的
I don't watch TV
那你知道有一种发明叫电视机…
Yeah, but you are aware that there's an invention called television
电视机上面要演电视节目吧？
and on this invention they show shows, right?
知道
Yeah
他们选择电视剧的方式就是先拍一集 这第一集就叫"样片"
The way they pick TV shows, they make one show  That show's called a pilot
拍好就给选片的人看
Then they show that one show to the people who pick shows
根据样片决定哪个可以继续拍下去
and on the strength of that one show they decide if they want to make more shows
被选中的就成为电视节目
Some get chosen and become television programs
没被选上就什么也不是
Some don't, become nothing
她演的就什么也不是
She starred in one of the ones that became nothing
你记得那个安特万・罗卡莫拉吗？
You remember Antwan Rockamora?
黑人和萨摩亚人混血的绰号叫“恐怖东尼”的那个
Half-black, half-Samoan used to call him "Tony Rocky Horror".
呃…那个胖子吗?
Yeah, maybe  Fat, right?
我才不会叫这哥们儿胖子呢 他确实有点超重
I wouldn't go so far as to call the brother fat  I mean, he got a weight problem
可这黑鬼能做什么？他是个萨摩亚裔！
（萨摩亚裔通常都超肥的）
What's the nigger gonna do, he's Samoan
我知道你说的是谁了他怎么了？
Yeah, I think I know who you mean  What about him?
马瑟勒斯把他修理惨了
Well, Marsellus fucked him up good
据说是因为马瑟勒斯・华莱士的老婆
Word around the campfire is it was on account of Marsellus Wallace's wife
他做了什么？操她了？      不不不 没这么糟
So, what'd he do, fuck her? No, no, no, no, no  Nothing that bad
那是怎么一回事?
Well, then, what, then?
替她做了脚部按摩
Gave her a foot massage
脚部按摩？
A foot massage?
仅此而已?
That's it?
马瑟勒斯怎么整的他?
Then what did Marsellus do?
派了几个手下去他的住处把他弄到公寓楼的露台上
Sent a couple of cats over to his place They took him out on his patio,
然后拖上阳台 黑鬼从四楼摔了下来
threw his ass over the balcony  Nigger fell four stories
楼下有个玻璃顶棚的小花园 像一个温室
They had a little garden down at the bottom enclosed in glass, like a greenhouse
那黑鬼就摔里面去了
Nigger fell through that
从那以后 他就变得口吃了
Since then, he kind of developed a speech impediment
太丢脸了！
That's a damn shame
几点了
What time you got?
七点二十二分
7:22 in the a m
还早 来 我们走走
No, it ain't quite time yet  Come on  Let's hang back
我不给男人做脚部按摩不代表马瑟勒斯是对的
Just 'cause I wouldn't give no man a foot massage don't make it right for Marsellus
把安特万从楼上仍进该死的玻璃花房摔成结巴太他妈过份了
to throw Antwan off a building into a glass motherfucking house fucking up the way the nigger talks
谁他妈要敢这样对我 他最好快来添我的屁股
That shit ain't right Motherfucker do that shit to me, he better paralyze my ass
因为我绝对要杀了那狗杂种报仇懂吗？
cause I'd kill the motherfucker you know what I'm saying?
我没说他是对的
I ain't saying it's right
但是你说脚部按摩根本没什么 这我不同意
But you're saying a foot massage don't mean nothing and I'm saying it does
我替很多女人做过脚部按摩 都“有什么”！
I've given a million ladies a million foot massages and they all meant something
大家都心照不宣 所以才他妈很爽！
Now, we act like they don't, but they do  That's what's so fucking cool about 'em
大家都能感觉到 但不会说破
There's a sensuous thing going on where, you know you don't talk about it
男女各自心知肚明
but you know it, and she knows it
马瑟勒斯很清楚 安特万更他妈清楚
Fucking Marsellus knew it and Antwan should've fucking better known better
伙计 那可是他老婆！可不能拿这事儿开玩笑！
I mean, that's his fucking wife, man  This ain't a man with a sense of humor about this shit
懂我的意思了吗?
You know what I'm saying?
很有意思…走吧 该干活了
It's an interesting point  Come on  Let's get into character
她叫什么来着?
What's her name again?
米娅  米娅
Mia  Mia
干嘛对老大的女人感兴趣?
Why you so interested in big man's wife?
老大要去趟弗罗里达 叫我搞定她
Well, he's going out of town, Florida and he asked me if I'd take care of her while he's gone
搞定她?      别想歪 老兄
Take care of her? No, man  Just take her out
我只是负责陪她寻乐子 不让她无聊而已
You know, show her a good time  Make sure she don't get lonely
你要带米娅・华莱士出去约会?
You're gonna be taking Mia Wallace out on a date?
不是约会
It is not a date
就像陪好友老婆出去玩玩
It's just like if you were going to take your buddy's wife to a movie or something
大家开开心罢了
It's just good company, that's all
这不算约会 绝对不算
It's not a date  It's definitely not a date
小崽子们 你们好吗?
Hey, kids  How you boys doing?
嘿…放轻松点
Hey, keep chilling
知道我们是谁吗?
You know who we are?
我们是你们的合伙人马塞勒斯・华莱士的朋友
We're associates of your business partner Marsellus Wallace
你们一定记得你们的合伙人 对吗?
You do remember your business partner, don't you?
让我来猜猜看
Let me take a wild guess here
你是布莱特?
You're Brett, right?
是的  我就知道
Yeah  I thought so
记得你合伙人马瑟勒斯・华莱士吗？布莱特?
You remember your business partner Marsellus Wallace don't you, Brett?
嗯…记…记得
Yeah, I remember him
很好 看来我和文森特打扰你们吃早餐了
Good  Looks like me and Vincent caught you boys at breakfast
真抱歉
Sorry about that
你们在吃什么?
What you having?
汉堡  汉堡?
Hamburgers  Hamburgers!
营养丰富的早餐哦！
The cornerstone of any nutritious breakfast
哪种汉堡?
What kind of hamburgers?
吉…吉士汉堡…
Ch-ch-cheeseburgers
不不不 我问你哪买的? 麦当劳？温蒂？杰克盒子？
No, no, no, no  Where'd you get 'em? McDonald's, Wendy's, Jack-in-the-Box, where?
大魔法师汉堡
Um, Big Kahuna Burger
大魔法师汉堡！那家夏威夷汉堡店
Big Kahuna Burger  That's that Hawaiian burger joint
我没试过 听说很棒 好吃吗?
I hear they got some tasty burgers  I ain't never had one myself  How are they?
好吃      介意我尝尝你的吗?
They're good  You mind if I try one of yours?
这是你的吧?  是的…
This is yours here, right? Yeah
嗯！这汉堡真棒！
Mmm! This is a tasty burger
文森 你吃过大魔法师汉堡吗?
Vincent, you ever had a Big Kahuna Burger?
尝一口 好吃极了
Want a bite? They're real tasty
我不饿
I ain't hungry
喜欢吃汉堡的人 一定得尝尝这个
If you like burgers, give 'em a try sometime
我…
Me,
我不能经常吃因为我马子是素食主义者
I can't usually get 'em ' cause my girlfriend's a vegetarian
她很想把我也变成素食主义者
which pretty much makes me a vegetarian
不过这汉堡真的很赞!
But I do love the taste of a good burger
知道在法国“吉士汉堡”怎么叫吗?
You know what they call a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese in France?
不知道     告诉他 文森特
No  Tell him, Vincent
皇家吉士堡
Royale with Cheese
知道为什么吗?
You know why they call it that?
因为他们用的是公制?
Because of the metric system?
你真是天才布莱特！
Check out the big brain on Brett!
你真他妈的聪明 公制 一点也不错
You're a smart motherfucker  That's right  The metric system
这是什么?
What's in this?
雪碧  很好
Sprite  Sprite, good
我可以喝一口把汉堡冲下去吗?
You mind if I have some of your tasty beverage to wash this down with?
请便
Go right ahead
过瘾！
That hit the spot
你 睡美人 知道我们为什么来吗？
You, Flock of Seagulls  You know why we're here?
最好告诉我兄弟文森特你们把那东西藏哪儿了?
Why don't you tell my man Vince here where you got the shit hid at?
在那里…     我他妈问你了吗？
It's over there  I don't remember asking you a goddamn thing!
你刚说什么?
You were saying?
在橱柜里
It's in the cupboard
不 你膝盖边的那个
N-no  The one by your kn-knees
满意吗？
We happy?
文森特？
Vincent?
满意吗?
We happy?
很满意
Yeah, we happy  Pbbbt
抱歉 我不知道你的名字
Look    I'm sorry, uh, l   I didn't get your name
你叫文森特 对吧? 但你呢?
I got yours  Uh, Vincent, right? But    but l    I never got yours
我叫皮特 你别想从中脱身
（皮特 pitt,音同pit,pit有凹陷 深渊的意思）
My name's Pitt and your ass ain't talking your way out of this shit
我只想让你们了解…
I just want you to know how
我想让你们知道我们有多后悔
I just want you to know how sorry we are
这事儿搞得我们和华莱士先生都很麻烦
that things got so fucked up with us and and Mr Wallace
不过 我们的初衷是美好的…
W-we got into this thing with the best intentions  I never
抱歉 我打断你讲话了吗?
Oh, I'm sorry  Did I break your concentration?
我不是故意的 请继续
I didn't mean to do that  Please, continue
你刚刚说到“美好的初衷”
You were saying something about  best intentions
怎么? 噢你说完了?
What's the matter? Oh, y-you were finished?
轮到我来反驳了
Oh, well, allow me to retort
马瑟勒斯・华莱士长什么样子?
What does Marsellus Wallace look like?
什么?
What?
你是哪国人?
What country are you from?
什么? 什么?
Wh-what?
我不知道有叫"什么"的国家? 他们讲英文吗?
Why no country I ever heard of, they speak English in What?
说英文 狗杂种 你会说英文吗?   会！
English, motherfucker! Do you speak it? Yes!
那你能听懂我的话吗?
Then you know what I'm saying
描述一下马瑟勒斯・华莱士长什么样子?
Describe what Marsellus Wallace looks like!
什么? 我…
What? I
再说一遍“什么” 再给我说一遍！
Say "what" again! Say "what" again!
你他妈的胆敢再说一遍“什么”试试!
I dare you! I double-dare you, motherfucker! Say "what" one more goddamn time!
他…他…是黑人       还有呢?
H-h-he's black  Go on!
他…是…秃子
He's bald
他像个婊子吗?
Does he look like a bitch?
什么?
What?
他像个婊子吗?
Does he look like a bitch?
不！
No!
你为什么想像操婊子一样操他?        我没有！
Then why you try to fuck him like a bitch, Brett? I didn't
是的你有 你有！布莱特 你想操他！
Yes, you did  Yes, you did, Brett! You tried to fuck him
除了她老婆马瑟勒斯・华莱士不喜欢被任何人操！
Marsellus Wallace don't like to be fucked by anybody except Mrs  Wallace
读过圣经吗?
You read the Bible, Brett?
读过
Y-yes
有段圣经现在读应该很合适
Well, there's this passage I got memorized
《以西结书》二十五章十七节
（以西结是书的作者 该书属于先知书 记载在《圣经・旧约》）
sort of fits this occasion  Ezekiel 25:17
正直之人的道路
The path of the righteous man
被小人的自私贪婪和恶人的暴虐专政所笼罩
is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men
以仁慈善良之名引领弱小穿越黑暗之谷的“牧羊人”
Blessed is he who in the name of charity and good will
必将得到神的护佑
shepherds the weak through the Valley of Darkness
因为他守护兄弟同胞 拯救迷途羔羊
for he is truly his brother's keeper and the finder of lost children
我将对那些毒害和屠杀我同胞的人
And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger
充满巨大的仇恨和爆裂的怒火！
those who attempt to poison and destroy My brothers
当我复仇之焰吞噬你的那刻 你会知道我的名字 叫做上帝！
And you will know My name is the Lord when I lay My vengeance upon thee!